Hello, in this notebook,
大家好 在这个 notebook 中
I'll be showing you how to train a neural network with PyTorch.
我将演示如何使用 PyTorch 训练神经网络
So, remember from the previous part we built a neural network but it wasn't
在之前的视频中 我们构建了神经网络
able to actually tell us what the digit was in these images.
但是它无法判断这些图像中的数字是多少
So, what we want is we want to be able to
我们希望能够向某个函数中
pass in an image into some function and this function
传入一个图像
is going to return to us
此函数将能够返回一个概率分布
a probability distribution that tells us that this is an image of a four.
告诉我们此图像是 4
So, what we're going to do here is
我们要做的是训练神经网络
actually train a neural network to approximate this function.
逼近此函数
The way you do that is you give it an image,
方法是传入一个图像
you tell it the right answer,
告诉它正确答案
and then the neural network learns how to approximate this function.
然后神经网络会学习如何逼近该函数
So, that is what we are going to be looking at in this notebook.
这就是我们将在此 notebook 中实现的目标
Just as a quick reminder of how training actually works is,
快速解释下训练的工作原理
as I was saying,
正如我刚才提到的
we pass in an image and then we also pass in the correct category,
我们传入一个图像并传入正确的类别
the correct label for it,
即正确的标签
and what we do is measure the difference between our networks prediction,
然后我们衡量网络预测结果（即这部分）
what this thing is, and the true label of that image.
与图像真实标签之间的差别
The difference between the prediction and the true label is called the loss.
预测结果和真实标签之间的差别称为误差
There's different ways to measure this,
误差有不同的衡量方式
for example, the mean squared loss or a cross entropy,
例如 均方损失或交叉熵
which we've seen, and you use this loss to update the weights.
我们之前见过 并且你使用此损失更新了权重
We do the updating through this iterative process called gradient descent.
我们通过这个叫做梯度下降的迭代流程更新权重
So, then the idea is that you have this gradient of your loss function,
原理是计算损失函数的梯度
which is basically the slope of the loss function,
即损失函数的斜率
and it always points in the direction of fastest change.
它始终指向变化最快的方向
We want to minimize our loss because that means that
我们希望最小化损失
our predictions are as close as possible to the true labels.
这样就意味着预测结果与真实标签越来越接近
So, it's great descent since it's always pointing in the direction of fastest change,
因此使用梯度下降 因为它始终指向变化最快的方向
this will get us to the bottom of our loss function the fastest way possible.
使我们能够尽快抵达损失函数的底部
With multilayer neural networks,
对于多层级神经网络
we do this through back propagation.
我们通过反向传播更新权重
Back propagation is really just an application of the chain rule.
反向传播实际上是链式法则的应用
So, what this means is that for a change in W1 that
也就是说 对于 W1 中的更改
change propagates all the way through this network from left to right,
此更改将一直在网络中反向传播 从左到右
all the way to the loss which is script L. Similarly,
一直到损失 即 L
the same changes they propagate backwards through the network to the 2W1, our weights.
同样 相同的更改在网络中反向传播到权重 2W1
So, to update our weights we actually need to know
要更新权重
the gradient of the loss with respect to our weights.
我们需要知道损失相对于权重的梯度
To do that, we can just multiply the gradients of each step in this series of operations.
为此 我们可以将这一系列运算中的每一步的梯度相乘
The first thing we need to do in PyTorch is define our loss function.
在 PyTorch 中 首先我们需要定义损失函数
You'll usually see the loss assigned to a variable called criterion.
通常损失会分配给叫做 criterion 的变量
So, if we're using the softmax output,
如果要使用 softmax 输出
we want our loss, our criterion,
我们需要将损失（即 criterion）设为交叉熵
to be cross-entropy loss so we can get that within nn.CrossEntropyLoss.
可以通过 nn.CrossEntropyLoss 获得该损失
Then later, we put in the output from our network and our true labels,
稍后 输入网络的输出和真实标签（即目标）
our targets to get the actual loss.
获得真实损失
We also need an optimizer.
还需要优化器
So the optimizer takes a loss.
优化器会接受损失
We'll also need an optimizer.
我们还需要优化器
Since we have a loss,
如果有损失
we can calculate our gradients and then once we have those gradients,
我们可以计算梯度 获得这些梯度后
the optimizer uses them to actually update all the weights in parameters in our network.
优化器会使用这些梯度更新网络中的所有权重和参数
So, for this, I'm going to be using stochastic gradient descent or SGD.
对于优化器 我们将使用随机梯度下降 简称 SGD
There's also more advanced optimizers like
还有更高级的优化器 例如 Adam
Adam but we won't be worrying about that right now.
暂时不需要了解 Adam
To calculate gradients, PyTorch uses a module called autograd.
为了计算梯度 PyTorch 会使用一个叫做 autograd 的模块
What autograd does is that if you have a tensor,
autograd 的作用是
and you tell it that it requires a gradient,
如果你有一个张量 告诉该张量它需要梯度
it tracks every single operation that happens on that tensor.
autograd 会跟踪发生在该张量上的每个运算
So then, at the end of your operations,
在运算结束时
you can say for example,
例如 z.backward
z.backward and then it does a backward pass through all the operations,
然后 autograd 会反向传播所有运算
and it kept track of all those things,
它会跟踪所有这些运算
and it knows the gradient functions for all those things.
知道所有这些运算的梯度函数
And so, we can go backwards and then
我们可以反向传播
eventually calculate all the gradients that you want.
最终计算所需的所有梯度
So, I'll show you how this works.
我将演示下工作原理
So first, I'm just going to import stuff like normal.
首先 正常地导入组件
Here, I'm just going to create a random tensor.
在这里创建一个随机张量
So this just going to be a two by two tensor,
大小是 2x2
just randomly sampled from a normal distribution.
从正态分布里随机抽样
We're going to say requires grad equals true.
输入 requires_grad=True
So, this will tell PyTorch to track
这行代码告诉 PyTorch
all the operations that happen on this tensor using auto grad.
使用 autograd 跟踪发生在此张量上的所有运算
Eventually, we'll be able to calculate
最终 我们将能够计算它的梯度
the gradient for it and that's what our tensor looks like.
这就是该张量的样貌
So, we can say y equals x squared and print y,
输入 y = x**2 print(y)
so it says squared r values.
对值求平方
If we do print.y.grad fun,
如果输入 print(y.grad_fn)
then this actually shows the operation that was done to get y.
它会显示为了获得 y 所执行的运算
So, we squared x here to
我们在这里对 x 求平方 创建了 y
create y and then if you look at the gradient function for y is its power.
查看 y 的梯度函数 这里是求幂
So, we took x to the power of two.
计算 x 的二次幂
So, eventually when we're going backwards to these operations,
最终 当我们反向通过这些运算时
it's going to use this gradient function to calculate the gradient for y.
将使用这个梯度函数计算 y 的梯度
So, now if we take the mean of y,
现在 如果计算 y 的均值
print that, it's now just a single number.
输出结果 是一个数字
We can check the gradients of x and y but there's nothing there.
我们可以检查 x 和 y 的梯度 但是什么也没有
So, there's nothing there because we haven't actually done
什么也没有的原因是
a backward pass through these operations yet.
我们尚未反向传播这些运算
So, we haven't actually asked PyTorch or Autograd to calculate the gradient yet.
我们尚未要求 PyTorch 或 Autograd 计算梯度
So, now to actually calculate our gradients,
要计算梯度
we need to go backward through these operations.
我们需要反向通过这些运算
For instance, if we want to do the gradient of z with respect to x,
例如 如果要计算 z 相对于 x 的梯度
then we say z.backward and this calculates the gradients of z with respect to x,
输入 z.backward() 它会计算 z 相对于 x 的梯度
then we can print this out and also print out.
输入 print 输出这个
So, based on the operations that we did,
根据我们执行的运算
we should expect that the gradient of z with respect to x should be x over two.
z 相对于 x 的梯度应该是 x/2
So, I'll just go and print that out too.
再次输出结果
So, we get our gradient and it is the same as x over two.
获得了梯度 和 x/2 一样
So, calculate gradient and it is what we expect.
计算梯度后的结果和预期一样
So, now I'm just going to grab our data and
现在我们将获取数据并构建网络
build the network like we did in the last part.
和在上一部分执行的操作一样
Now we have our model and now I'm going to actually train it.
我们已经有了模型 现在将训练该模型
So like I said before,
和之前提到的一样
we need to define our loss or our criterion.
我们需要定义损失函数 criterion
So, criterion is equal to nn.CrossEntropyLoss and then we can define our optimizer.
输入 criterion = nn.CrossEntropyLoss 然后定义优化器
Optimizer optim.SGD.
输入 optimizer = optim.SGD
Then for the optimizer,
对于优化器来说
we need to pass in the parameters that we actually want to optimize.
我们需要传入想要优化的参数
So, in this case, you want to optimize all the parameters of our model.
在此示例中 我们想要优化模型的所有参数
So, we say model.parameters and then we need to set the learning rate,
因此输入 model.parameters() 然后设置学习速率
so learning rate here is going to be 0.01.
在此示例中 将学习速率设为 0.01
Then, the general process with PyTorch is first we're going to
对于 PyTorch 来说 一般步骤是
make a forward pass through the network to get our output,
对网络进行前向传播以获得输出
or logits, or a softmax,
例如 logit 或 softmax
whatever the output of your network is.
或其他网络输出
Then we're going to use that output to calculate the loss.
我们将使用该输出计算损失
Then once you have the loss,
获得损失后
you can do a backward pass through the network with loss.backward and this will
可以使用 loss.backward 反向通过网络
calculate the gradients for all the parameters in your network.
这样会计算网络中所有参数的梯度
Then with the gradients you can take a step with the optimizer to update the weights.
获得梯度后 可以使用优化器更新权重
So, first I'm going to do is actually print out the weights before
我将输出训练网络之前的权重
our little training pass, model.fc1.weight.
输入 model.fc1.weight
Then we get our images and labels like
然后正常地获取图像和标签
normal but the first thing you actually have to do is call optimizer.zero_grad.
但是首先需要调用 optimizer.zero_grad()
So, what this does is it zeros out all the gradients set are on tensors,
这行代码的作用是使张量上的所有梯度
weights, and biases that are being trained.
被训练的权重和偏差归零
So, the reason you need to do this is because every time
需要这么做的原因是
you do backwards like if you do loss.backward,
每次反向传播时 例如 loss.backward
it actually accumulates the gradients.
会积累梯度
So, that means that if you go through twice then it's going to
意味着如果反向传播两次
add the two gradient calculations again,
会再次加上这两个梯度运算
and then if you do it a third time, it's going to add all three of those,
如果反向传播第三次 则加上这三个梯度运算
if you do it a fourth time it's going to add all four of those and so in general,
如果反向传播第四次 则加上这四个梯度运算
you don't want to do that.
总之 你不希望出现这种现象
You just want it to do one pass, get your gradients,
只希望传播一次 获得梯度
use those gradients to train, and then the next pass,
使用这些梯度训练网络 然后下次传播时
calculate new gradients and use those gradients to train.
计算新的梯度并使用这些梯度训练网络
So, if you don't zero grad and basically you are summing up,
如果不归零的话 则会累积起来
you're accumulating gradients over multiple training passes and multiple batches.
使多次训练传播和多个批次的梯度累积起来
The first thing in your training pass is
在训练传播中的第一件事
typically you want to make sure that you zero out the gradients.
通常是确保归零梯度
So, now we can do our forward pass.
现在可以前向传播了
In the output, is going to be model.forward,
输入 output = model.forward
pass in our images,
传入图像
calculate the loss with our criterion,
使用我们的 criterion 计算损失
where we pass in our output and the true labels,
在这里传入输出和真实标签
and then go into do our backward pass.
然后反向传播
So, this is going to calculate the gradients for all of our parameters.
它将计算所有参数的梯度
Then here I can actually print out the gradients.
在这里输出梯度
Now, with the gradients,
对于梯度
we're going to take an optimizer step and update our weights.
我们可以执行优化步骤 更新权重
That's what it looks like before,
这是训练之前的样子
here are our gradients,
这是梯度
and now we can look at our updated weights.
这是更新后的权重
So, basically, it took our gradients,
也就是获取梯度
added it to our existing parameters,
使用某个学习速率加到现有参数上
our weights with some learning rate,
即权重上
and we have updated weights.
获得更新后的权重
So, this little bit right here is,
这部分代码
this whole cell, is really just a basic training pass.
这整个单元格就是一个基本训练传播
We get some images and labels from our train loader,
我们从 trainloader 获得图像和标签
which loads our data,
trainloader 会加载数据
and then we pass it forward through our model, calculate the loss,
然后使数据传入模型中 计算损失
do backwards pass through our network,
对网络反向传播
and then we take an optimizer step.
执行优化步骤
You can wrap this whole thing in
可以将这整个步骤封装到 for 循环里
a for-loop that goes through all of your images and labels,
遍历所有的图像和标签
everything in your dataset and updates
即数据集中的所有数据
your network and that's how your network basically learns.
更新网络 这就是网络的训练方式
So, now we can take this training method and put it in a loop.
现在 我们可以将这个训练方法放入循环中
So, what you typically do is define the number of epochs you want to train it on.
采用的方式是定义要训练的周期数量
So, basically, one epoch is one pass through
一个周期是
the entire dataset and so three epochs
经过整个数据集一次
is going to be three passes through the entire dataset.
三个周期是经过整个数据集三次
Just defining some things which I'll use.
定义一些要使用的参数
So for E in epochs,
输入
for range in range epochs.
for e in range(epochs)
So, defining running loss.
定义 running_loss
So we're going to actually be printing out our loss as we're training so we can
训练过程中 我们将输出损失
see that the training losses like the loss of our network is actually dropping.
以便检查训练损失（网络损失）是否真的下降了
So, as our network learns and its predictions become better,
当网络不断学习时 预测会越来越准确
then the loss is going to decrease and so we
损失将下降
just want to see that's happening as we're training.
我们希望看到训练过程中出现这一效果
So, we get our images and labels from the train loader.
从 trainloader 获取图像和标签
We're going to keep track of our steps,
跟踪时间步
so how many times we've actually trained.
即训练了多少次
So again, images.resize.
再次输入 images.resize
Okay, so now our training pass.
现在是训练传播步骤
So, optimizer.zero_grad.
输入 optimizer.zero_grad()
Now our forward pass,
前向传播
output model.forward, loss equals criterion.
输入 output = model.forward loss = criterion
Our backward pass and then our weight update step.
反向传播 然后是更新权重步骤
Here, our loss is just a single number so what this means it's a scalar tensor.
这里 损失只是一个数字 也就是它是一个标量张量
To actually get this number out of the scalar tensor and just summit with a zero here,
要从标量张量中获取这个数字 与这个 0 相加
then we actually need to do a loss.item.
我们需要执行 loss.item
Every so often going to print out our training loss.
然后多次输出训练损失
Okay and so we can see, just scroll down,
好了 往下滚动
that our training loss is dropping as its training which is a good sign.
可以看出当网络不断训练时 训练损失一直在下降 这是个好现象
Now with the network trained,
训练好网络后
we can see how it performs.
可以看看它的性能如何
Here, we are passing in the image of number six to
我们向网络中传入数字 6
our network and then our network has learned that this is a number six.
网络知道这是数字 6
We can look at different numbers so it knows that a two is a two.
传入不同的数字 它知道 2 是 2
It knows that a three is a three, so it's really cool.
知道 3 是 3  很酷
Now using back propagation,
借助反向传播
we were able to train our neural network to identify these images of handwritten digits.
我们能够训练神经网络识别这些手写数字图像
This is useful for things like scanning documents, right?
这对扫描文档来说很有用 对吧
You can imagine that you can just take a whole bunch of images of a document,
可以想象 对文档拍摄大量照片
and it kind of scan over it,
扫描文档
and then pass the images into a network,
然后将图像传入网络中
and the network is able to basically tell
网络能够根据文档图像
your computer what is in this document just from an image of a document.
告诉计算机文档中的内容是什么
In the next part, you'll be able to, again,
在下个部分 你将能够再次构建你自己的网络
build your own network and train it this time. Cheers.
并且这次能够训练网络 加油